Which health insurance plan
is better for you: ICICI Lord Elevate, Niva Mopa
Aspire, Titanium Plus, or Ta NG Medical
Premium? Today, we will do a detailed comparison of
three popular health insurance plans.
If you want to choose the best policy for yourself and your family, then definitely
watch this video. Let's start with entry age. For
ICICI Lord Elevate,
coverage for adults starts from six years
and there is no upper age limit. This
flexibility is also good for older adults.
Children can be
covered under the floater plan in the age group between 91 days and 5 years. For
Niva Mopa Aspire,
adult
coverage starts from 18 years and there is
no upper age limit. Children
can be covered from 91 days. For Ta NG Medicare
Premier, coverage
starts from 18 years and the maximum entry
age is 65.5 years. Children can be covered from 91 days.
Talking about Aazi Medicate Premier, the
maximum entry age for adults is 65 years and
children can be covered up to 25 years.
Now coming to the sum in short, ICICI
Loma Elevate has a minimum of ₹7.5 lakh and a
maximum of unlimited. This plan offers high coverage
amounts without any gap.
Talking about Titanium Plus, the minimum is ₹
3 lakh and the maximum is ₹1 crore. This range
provides moderate coverage.
Coming to Aazi Medicate Premier, it has a minimum of ₹
5 lakh and a maximum of ₹3 crore. This plan
also offers substantial coverage but
with an upper limit. Now let's talk about its
maximum entry age. There is no
upper age limit for coverage for adults in ICICI Loma Elevate,
which
is very beneficial for older individuals. Children can be
covered up to 30 years. In N V Spy Titanium
Plus, the maximum entry age for adults is
65 years.  And children can be covered up to 30 years.
Now coming to the room rent
limit, a
single private room is covered in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan, and if you
select DON, there is no room rent
limit. Titanium Plus has no room rent limit,
giving you flexibility in choosing any type of hospital room.
Talking about AG Medicel Premier, there is no room rent limit either.
Now coming to pre-hospitalization
and post-hospitalization,
pre-
hospitalization is covered up to 90 days in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan, and
post-hospitalization is covered up to 180 days. Talking about NIBA Papa
Spa Titanium Plus, pre-
hospitalization is covered up to 60 days and
post-hospitalization is covered up to 180 days.
Talking about AG Medicel Premier,
pre-hospitalization is covered up to 60 days and
post-hospitalization is covered up to 90 days.
Now, let's talk about day care
treatments. ICCI Lombard Daily Vet covers
all day care treatments.  Covered which
includes treatments that do
not require 24-hour hospitalization
Now let's talk about Restoration
Benefit The
details of Restoration Benefit are
not specified in ICCI Lombard Abbott but you should check
if Restoration Benefit is included
Unlimited Restoration for all illnesses
is available in Nepai Spay Titanium Plus which ensures that your sum
insured is replenished without any limit
One time
restoration for unrelated illnesses is available in TA AG Medic Premier Restoration
for related illnesses is available
after 45 days Now coming to waiting
periods In ICICI Lombard Elevate
Initial waiting period is 30 days Pre
assisting disease PD waiting period is 36
months which can be reduced to 24 or 12 months
Specific treatment
disease waiting period is 24  Months 90 Days for
BP, Diabetes, Heart Conditions, etc.
PD can be reduced from 1st to 24 Months
Talking about Niva PAP Spy Titanium Plus, the initial waiting period is 30 days
PD waiting period is 36 months Specific
treatment disease waiting period is 24 months
Tata AG Medicel Premier has an initial
waiting period of 30 days PD waiting period is 24 months
Specific treatment disease waiting
period is 24 months Now let's talk about Key
US Peace ICICI Lara Elevate Key Super
No Claim Bonus 100% No Claim Bonus is available every year
and
coverage can be extended up to unlimited service in short Now let's talk about Niva PAP
Spy Titanium Age Lock
Your age is locked on policy purchase and premiums are
fixed at the entry age until a
claim is made Global Cover
If you go for treatment abroad after being diagnosed with an illness in India, then
this plan covers you  The
cost is covered Talking about Tata AG Medicate
Premier, Global Cover covers
treatment after diagnosis in India and abroad,
which
provides you with international treatment options
Hopefully, these comparisons will
help you in taking a decision. Choose the policy keeping in
mind your specific needs and preferences.
So that is all
for this video. If you found this video
helpful, then like, share and
subscribe to Essential Insurance
[Sangeet]